these are three functional array methods
that every javascript developer should
know
that find helps us look for an item
inside of an array and the way we use it
is like this that's fine just like all
the other methods on this video has only
one required parameter and that is a
callback function the callback function
is not going to be called by us we just
put the name of the function and
javascript is going to call the function
and is also going to call it with very
helpful arguments in the case of that
find javascript will call the find
avocado function with each fruit of the
fruit array on the first argument so
basically what is going on behind the
scenes is javascript doing something
like this
now this isn't actual code it's just the
way i like to imagine it to make it
easier to understand the name of the
parameter on the callback function does
not matter i named it current fruit but
you can name it whatever you want what
is important is the position let's now
take a look at what the find avocado
function is doing now each method on
this video and in javascript has a
different rule of what a callback
function does the rule for that find is
that if the callback function returns
true that means that we have found the
item that we are looking for in our find
avocado function the condition will be
true if the current fruit that we are
receiving from javascript is equal to
the avocado else it will return false
after our find avocado function returns
true the current item that is being
processed is going to be the resulting
value of the dot find function and that
is the value that our avocado constant
is going to hold
that map allows us to take elements from
an array transform them and put them on
a new array that map will not modify the
source array instead it will create a
new one with the transformed items now
the way we use it is something like this
just like what we saw on that find the
callback function will be called for
each item of the array and the first
argument will be the item that is
currently being processed so to make it
easier to understand you can imagine
that something like this is happening
behind the scenes remember this is not
real code it's just an example to make
it easier for us to understand what's
going on the rule for that map is that
the value returned by the callback
function will be the value that will be
in our new array right now our callback
function is receiving each of the
numbers in the source array inside of
the current number argument and is
returning that current number times 2.
that means that when the that map
function finishes the value of the
transform constant on our code will be
an array with the same length as the
source array but with the numbers
doubled now it's very important to
remember that the callback function has
to return something if you forget to
return like in this code for example
then the result will be an array of the
same length of the source array but full
of undefined
now for the last method on this video
we're going to use a new syntax a
different way of writing our functions
what we're going to do now is we're
going to use arrow functions with arrow
functions we can modify that fine and
that map examples from looking like this
to looking something like this now as
you can see that looks much much better
now don't be scared by this syntax it's
very easy to understand all arrow
functions do is they allow us to write a
function in one line of code instead of
having to type the word function in
parentheses and brackets and all those
things we can just do it in one line of
code and it's very easy to understand
first we write the arguments of the
function and after the arrow we write
the return value that's it the
superpower of the arrow function is that
it has something called a implicit
return that means that we don't need to
write the return keyword to return
something whatever you put after the
arrow that will be returned
automatically before we were using our
functions javascript was doing something
like this behind the scenes
and now with our functions javascript is
going to do something like this behind
the scenes as you can see it's almost
very similar now before we move on to
the last method on this list please
remember that if you want to learn
javascript for free with me all you have
to do is click the link below there
you're going to find an eight hour free
javascript course for a hundred percent
javascript beginner so if you want to
become a developer you want to do it
with javascript and you want to do it
with me please click the link below and
i will see you there
that filter allows us to remove an item
from an array now actually that is not
really true that filter just like that
map they don't modify the source array
what that filter will do is that filter
will create a new array without the
items that you don't want to be there
and the way we use it using arrow
functions is like this now the rule of
the callback function for that filter is
very very easy if we return true then
the item that is currently being
processed is going to end up in the new
array if we return false then that item
that is being processed is going to be
excluded from the new array now here we
have an array of foods that contains
fruits and one corn we want to keep only
the fruits so in our call back function
we are checking if the current food
being processed is not equals to corn if
it's not corn then that food is going to
end up in our new array if it is corn
then that condition will return false
which means that we have to exclude that
item which is corn from our fruits array
there are other methods like for example
that sort that flat and that reduce that
i think are very useful as well let me
know in the comments if you would like
me to make videos about those methods
and also let me know in the comments if
you would like me to make videos like
this one but for programming languages
like maybe python java or csharp thank
you for watching this video if you like
this content and you would like to
support the channel then please leave a
like and subscribe it's two clicks it's
free for you but it helps me a lot thank
you so much for watching thank you for
your support thank you for your love
stay free stay happy eat kimchi
kamzamida salaam heyo see you on the
next one bye